Register to The David Stanley Smith Papers
Yale University Library
Irving S. Gilmore Music Library
The David Stanley Smith Papers
1889-1958 (inclusive)
Smith, David Stanley, 1877-1949.
MSS 31
40 boxes (21 linear feet)
Music, correspondence and other papers, photographs, and additional materials by and about the American composer, conductor, and educator David Stanley Smith (1877-1949)
Irving S. Gilmore Music Library, Yale University P.O. Box 208240 120 High Street New Haven, CT 06520-8240 Email: musiclibrary@yale.edu Phone: (203) 432-0492 Fax: (203) 432-7339
Administrative Information
Information about Access
The Papers are open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Provenance
The David Stanley Smith Papers were established in the Music Library of Yale University by Cora Welch Smith in 1950. Miscellaneous additional material was given to the Library in 1977 by Smith's son, Christopher S. Smith.
Arrangement
In 8 series as follows: I. Music. II. Correspondence. III. Clippings. IV. Programs. V. Photographs. VI. Works by and about David Stanley Smith. VII. Royalty statements and agreements. VIII. Memorabilia.
Description of the Papers
The David Stanley Smith Papers include sketches, manuscript scores, and printed editions of Smith's musical compositions, including orchestral music, keyboard works, chamber pieces, songs, and choral music. Smith's life and work are also documented by: correspondence; programs; photographs; clippings and biographical materials; and miscellaneous items.
Biographical Sketch
David Stanley Smith was born in Toledo, Ohio, on July 6, 1877. He grew up in a musical household, and by the age of fifteen he had found employment as a church organist. In 1895 he went to Yale, where Charles Ives (Class of 1898) was numbered among his friends; he would later serve as the organist at Center Church in New Haven, a position formerly held by Ives. Smith was an outstanding student, and he became the protégé of Professor Horatio Parker. Smith's graduation ceremony in 1900 featured a performance of his Ode for Commencement Day, conducted by Parker. After college, Smith traveled throughout Europe, where he took lessons with Ludwig Thuille and Charles-Marie Widor.
In 1903 Smith returned to Yale as an instructor in music theory. He would remain a member the Yale faculty until his retirement in 1946. Horatio Parker died in 1919, and the next year Smith succeeded him as Dean of the School of Music, a post he would hold until 1940. Again following in Parker's footsteps, he also became the conductor of the New Haven Symphony Orchestra.
Despite his duties as a teacher, administrator, and conductor, Smith was able to compose a substantial amount of music, including one opera, Merrymount, five symphonies, ten string quartets, many sacred works, and a variety of other compositions.
Smith married Cora Deming Welch in 1913. They had one son, Christopher Stanley Smith.
David Stanley Smith died in New Haven on December 17, 1949.
Access Terms
Smith, David Stanley, 1877-1949.; Angell, James Rowland, 1869-1949.; Balaban, Emanuel.; Ballantine, Edward, 1886-1971.; Baumgartner, H. Leroy (Hope Leroy), 1891-1969.; Bellamann, Henry, 1882-1945.; Bodanzky, Artur, 1877-1939.; Boulanger, Nadia.; Burgin, Richard.; Cohn, Arthur, 1910-; Cross, Wilbur L. (Wilbur Lucius), 1862-1948.; De Lamarter, Eric, 1880-1953.; Engel, Carl, 1883-1944.; Gabrilowitsch, Ossip, 1878-1936.; Graves, Henry S.; Hanson, Howard, 1896-; Hunt, Pearson.; Johnson, H. Earle (Harold Earle), 1903-1988.; Kirshbaum, Joseph.; Kroll, William, 1901-; Low, A. Augustus.; McKay, George Frederick, 1899-; Nettleton, George Henry, 1874-1959.; Noss, Luther.; Porter, Quincy, 1897-1966.; Poynter, Horace Martin.; Sektberg, Willard.; Seymour, Charles, 1885-1963.; Shepherd, Arthur, 1880-1958.; Simonds, Bruce.; Stevenson, Robert Murrell.; Tuthill, Burnet, 1888-1982.; Vaughan Williams, Ralph, 1872-1958.; Walter, Bruno, 1876-1962.; Westervelt, Louise St. John.; Music--United States--20th century.; Composers--Correspondence.; Organ music.; Piano music.; Songs.; String quartets--Scores.; Symphonies--Scores.
Collection Contents
- Music, I
  This series is divided into nine subseries (A-J) by genre. Cross-references have been made from parts of works to the title under which they are described. Transcription of the title page is given only when it contains information not stated in the uniform title. Many of the published works were previously catalogued, and any cards containing extra information have been laid in with their respective works. The term "bis," which occurs occasionally beside an opus number in a uniform title, is taken from the old cataloging where it was used to distinguish items with the same opus number. Subseries A-H are arranged alphabetically by title. The subseries J (Miscellaneous works) is divided into: Cadenzas, piano; Exercises; Juvenilia; Lists; Sketches; and Works by Others, with the works arranged alphabetically by title under these broad headings.
  - Orchestral Works, I.A
    - Alastor, op. 13
      See: Elegy, orchestra, op. 13.
    - [L'allegro and il penseroso, orchestra, op. 9] Two contrasted pieces for orchestra. I. L'allegro. II. Il penseroso.
      See also: Symphony, op. 9, C minor.
      - [L'allegro and il penseroso, orchestra, op. 9] Two contrasted pieces for orchestra. I. L'allegro. II. Il penseroso., 1 score (54 p.); 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 1)
        Holograph signed, in ink.
      - [L'allegro and il penseroso, orchestra, op. 9] Two contrasted pieces for orchestra. I. L'allegro. II. Il penseroso., 37 parts; 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 2)
        Holographs signed, in ink.
    - [Allegro giocoso, orchestra, op. 17] 1906 Feb 2
      - [Allegro giocoso, orchestra, op. 17] 1906 Feb 2, 1 score (40 p.); 36 cm. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - [Allegro giocoso, orchestra, op. 17] 1906 Feb 2, 45 parts; 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - [The apostle, orchestra, op. 92] The apostle: poem for orchestra: op. 92 1944 Nov 15
      - [The apostle, orchestra, op. 92] The apostle: poem for orchestra: op. 92 1944 Nov 15, 3 scores (52 p. each), 1 bound; 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 5)
        The closing section was taken from his tone-poem The golden age.
      - [The apostle, orchestra, op. 92] The apostle: poem for orchestra: op. 92 1944 Nov 15, 27 parts; 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - [The apostle, orchestra, op. 92] The apostle: poem for orchestra: op. 92 1944 Nov 15, 5 string parts; 31 cm. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - [The apostle, orchestra, op. 92] The apostle: poem for orchestra: op. 92 1944 Nov 15, 34 parts, bound; 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 6)
        Photocopies.
    - [The apostle, orchestra, op. 92 (Sketches)], 12 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Holograph signed, in pencil.
      See also: The golden age, op. 40.
    - [Concert overture, op. 1, E flat major] [1898], 1 score (40 p.); 27 x 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Incomplete, p. 41 to end wanting.
      "Composed 1898" -- card.
    - Contrasted pieces, orchestra, op. 9.
      See: L'allegro and il penseroso, orchestra, op. 9.
    - [Credo, orchestra, op. 83] 1941 Mar 5
      - [Credo, orchestra, op. 83] 1941 Mar 5, 2 scores (40 p. each), bound; 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - [Credo, orchestra, op. 83] 1941 Mar 5, 57 parts; 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 9)
        Mostly holographs signed, in ink.
        Some in Julian Menken's hand.
        Entitled: 'Poem-"Credo."'
    - [Darkness and dawn, op. 5] Darkness and dawn: symphonic poem for full orchestra: opus 5. 1901 Apr, 1 score (45 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - A dramatic lyric, op. 13.
    - [Elegy, orchestra, op. 13] (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - A dramatic lyric: also called Alastor (in revision): opus 16 [sic] 1906 Jan 27, 1 score (25 p.); 36 cm.
      - Alastor: a poem for orchestra: opus 16 [sic] 1907, 1 score (28 p.); 35 cm.
    - [Epic poem, orchestra, op. 55] 1925 Aug 15 (Box 30)
      - [Epic poem, orchestra, op. 55] 1925 Aug 15, 1 score (70 p.), bound; 43 cm.
      - [Epic poem, orchestra, op. 55] 1925 Aug 15, 1 score (70 p.), bound; 42 cm.
        Holograph signed, in ink with corrections in pencil.
        Sheet with corrections in pencil laid in.
        "There is a later revision, 1935" -- title page.
      - [Epic poem, orchestra, op. 55] 1925 Aug 15, 1 score (70 p.), bound; 41 cm.
      - [Epic poem, orchestra, op. 55] 1925 Aug 15, 66 parts; 36 cm. (Box 3, Folder 11-13)
        Holographs signed, in ink, and photocopies.
      - [Epic poem, orchestra, op. 55] 1925 Aug 15, 3 string parts; 35 cm. (Box 3, Folder 11-13)
        Viola, violoncello, and bass parts only.
    - [Flowers, orchestra, op. 52] 1924 Jul-Aug
      - [Flowers, orchestra, op. 52] 1924 Jul-Aug, 1 score (83 p.), bound; 34 cm.
        Contents: 1. The garden -- 2. Fading lilies -- 3. Haidenröslein -- 4. Daffodils - plucked!
      - [Flowers, orchestra, op. 52] 1924 Jul-Aug, 1 score (83 p.); 35 cm. (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - [Flowers, orchestra, op. 52] 1924 Jul-Aug, 11 parts; 34 cm. (Box 3, Folder 15)
        Manuscript in ink.
    - [The golden age, op. 40] The golden age: tone poems on Greek subjects for orchestra 1916 Aug 26 (Box 30)
      - [The golden age, op. 40] The golden age: tone poems on Greek subjects for orchestra 1916 Aug 26, 1 score (109 p.), bound; 42 cm.
        Part of this was used in the closing section of his tone-poem The apostle.
      - [The golden age, op. 40] The golden age: tone poems on Greek subjects for orchestra 1916 Aug 26, 1 score (101 p.); 45 cm. (Box 30, Folder 1)
        Holograph signed, in ink with many corrections.
        Contents: 1. Olympus -- 2. An Athenian festival -- 3. Choric dance -- 4. Idyl - the death of Daphnis (after Theocritus) -- 5. At a performance of tragedy.
      - [The golden age, op. 40] The golden age: tone poems on Greek subjects for orchestra 1916 Aug 26, 18 parts; 35 cm. (Box 3, Folder 16)
        Mostly III. Choric Dance, some IV. Idyl. The death of Daphnis.
    - [Impressions, orchestra, op. 40b] Impressions: four pieces for orchestra., 59 parts; 34 cm. (Box 3; 4, Folder 17-18; 19)
      Portions of this work appear also in The golden age, op. 40.
      Contents: Masque -- Shepherds idyl -- Greek dance -- Carnival.
    - Little symphony, op. 65, no. 1.
      See: Sinfonietta, string orchestra, op. 65, no. 1.
    - [Melodies, orchestra, op. 50] Four melodies.
      - [Melodies, orchestra, op. 50] Four melodies., 1 score (72 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 30)
        Another number was later inserted between no. 2 and no. 3; see below, Five melodies, op. 50.
        Contents: 1. Serioso -- 2. Delicato -- 3. Con grazia -- 4. Recitativo e aria.
      - [Melodies, orchestra, op. 50] Four melodies., 55 parts; 35 cm. (Box 4, Folder 20-22)
        Manuscript in ink (the harp part is the composer's holograph.)
        There are actually 5 melodies, but the third (Molto moderato - funebre) has been crossed out.
        Contents: Sereno (adagio molto) -- Delicato (allegro ma non troppo) -- [Molto moderato funebre] -- Con grazia (andantino vivace.) -- Recitativo e ario (allegro vivace.)
    - [Melodies, orchestra, op. 50] Five melodies 1924 Jul 8
      - [Melodies, orchestra, op. 50] Five melodies 1924 Jul 8, 1 score (67, 21 p.); 41 cm. (Box 30, Folder 2)
        Contents: 1. Adagio molto - serio -- 2. Allegro ma non troppo - piace vole -- 3. Molto moderato - mesto -- 4. Allegretto moderato -- 5. Allegro vivace.
      - [Melodies, orchestra, op. 50] Five melodies 1924 Jul 8, 1 score (74 p.), bound; 42 cm. (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - [Nineteen-twenty-nine, orchestra, op. 66, no. 1] "1929" - a satire. 1932 Aug 2
      - [Nineteen-twenty-nine, orchestra, op. 66, no. 1] "1929" - a satire. 1932 Aug 2, 1 score (83 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 4)
      - [Nineteen-twenty-nine, orchestra, op. 66, no. 1] "1929" - a satire. 1932 Aug 2, 1 score (83 l.), bound; 38 cm. (Box 4)
        Photocopy of holograph.
        Program notes for performance by Philharmonic-Symphony Society of N.Y., Bruno Walter conductor, 1933 Nov 17, laid in.
      - [Nineteen-twenty-nine, orchestra, op. 66, no. 1] "1929" - a satire. 1932 Aug 2, 1 score (83 l.); 34 cm. (Box 4, Folder 23)
        Photocopy (negative) of holograph.
      - [Nineteen-twenty-nine, orchestra, op. 66, no. 1] "1929" - a satire. 1932 Aug 2, 199 parts; 35 cm. (Box 5, Folder 24-29)
        Partly holographs signed, in ink, partly photocopies of holograph.
    - [Nineteen-twenty-nine, orchestra, op. 66, no. 1 (Sketches)], 13, [2] p. of music, bound; 31 cm. (Box 18, Folder 138)
      Holograph in pencil.
      Included in sketchbook with Quartet, strings, op. 62, D major.
      See also: Tomorrow, orchestra, op. 66, no. 2.
    - [Ouverture joyeuse, op. 11] 1903 May
      - [Ouverture joyeuse, op. 11] 1903 May, 1 score (47 p.); 35 cm. (Box 5, Folder 30)
        Op. 12 crossed out and changed to 11.
      - [Ouverture joyeuse, op. 11] 1903 May, 41 parts; 34 cm. (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - [Ouverture sérieuse, op. 12 (Sketch)], 1 score (14 p.); 35 cm. (Box 5, Folder 32)
      "Sketch of Ouverture sérieuse goes with Ouverture Joyeuse" -- title page.
    - [The passing of Oedipus, orchestra, op. 98] The passing of Oedipus: prelude for orchestra. 1947
      - [The passing of Oedipus, orchestra, op. 98] The passing of Oedipus: prelude for orchestra. 1947, 1 score (54 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 6)
        "Composed 1947" -- card.
        Sheet laid in: "Closing scene of Sophocles' Oedipus at Colonus."
      - [The passing of Oedipus, orchestra, op. 98] The passing of Oedipus: prelude for orchestra. 1947, 1 condensed score (16 sheets); 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 33)
        Holograph transparencies signed, in ink.
      - [The passing of Oedipus, orchestra, op. 98] The passing of Oedipus: prelude for orchestra. 1947, 3 condensed scores (16 p. each), bound; 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 33)
        Photocopies of above.
        One copy without title page, one with a note laid in.
      - [The passing of Oedipus, orchestra, op. 98] The passing of Oedipus: prelude for orchestra. 1947, 31 parts; 32 cm. (Box 6, Folder 34)
        Part holographs signed, in ink.
    - [Pieces, string orchestra, op. 89] 1943 Jul 7
      - [Pieces, string orchestra, op. 89] 1943 Jul 7, 1 score (40 sheets); 33 cm. (Box 6, Folder 35)
        Contents: I. Dance of youth -- II. The pensive violin -- III. Phantom troops -- IV. Persistent theme.
      - [Pieces, string orchestra, op. 89] 1943 Jul 7, 5 scores (40 p. each), bound; 33 cm. (Box 6, Folder 35)
        Photocopies of above score.
      - Four pieces (string orchestra), 47 string parts; 32 cm. (Box 6, Folder 36)
        Holograph transparencies, in ink.
      - [Pieces, string orchestra, op. 89] 1943 Jul 7, 30 parts, bound; 35 cm. (Box 6-7)
        Photocopies of above string parts.
    - [A poem of youth, orchestra, op. 47] 1920 Aug 21
      - [A poem of youth, orchestra, op. 47] 1920 Aug 21, 2 scores (75 p. each), bound; 41 cm. (Box 30)
      - [A poem of youth, orchestra, op. 47] 1920 Aug 21, 98 parts; 35 cm. (Box 7, Folder 37-41)
        Holographs in ink, except for strings, which are facsimiles.
    - [Prince Hal, op. 31]
      - Prince Hal: an overture. -- New York: G. Schirmer, 1915., 3 scores (65 p. each), bound; 35 cm. (Box 8)
        One contains markings.
      - [Prince Hal, op. 31], 134 parts; 31-35 cm. (Box 8, Folder 42-44)
        Includes several manuscript parts.
    - [Prince Hal, op. 31 (Sketches)], [34], 37, [35] p. of music, bound; 10 x 16 cm. (Box 5, Folder 32)
      Holograph signed, in pencil and ink.
      Also contains sketches for unidentified work.
    - [Sinfonietta, string orchestra, op. 65, no. 1] 1931 Aug 24
      - [Sinfonietta, string orchestra, op. 65, no. 1] 1931 Aug 24, 1 score (21 p.); 35 cm. (Box 8, Folder 45)
        Also known by title: Little symphony.
      - [Sinfonietta, string orchestra, op. 65, no. 1] 1931 Aug 24, 1 score (42 p.); 35 cm. (Box 8, Folder 45)
      - [Sinfonietta, string orchestra, op. 65, no. 1] 1931 Aug 24, 29 parts; 35 cm. (Box 8, Folder 46-48)
        Holograph transparencies signed, in ink, and copies.
    - [Sinfonietta, string orchestra, op. 65, no. 1 (Sketches)], 6 p. of music, bound; 32 cm. (Box 19, Folder 160)
      Included in sketchbook with Sextet: D.
      See also: E. Keyboard works. Sinfonietta, string orchestra, op. 65, no. 1; arr.
    - [Sonatina, string orchestra, op. 65, no. 2] Sonatina for junior string orchestra. 1932 Dec 13
      - [Sonatina, string orchestra, op. 65, no. 2] Sonatina for junior string orchestra. 1932 Dec 13, 1 score (19 p.); 35 cm. (Box 9, Folder 49)
      - [Sonatina, string orchestra, op. 65, no. 2] Sonatina for junior string orchestra. 1932 Dec 13, 14 parts; 35 cm. (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Symphonic adagio.
      See: J. Miscellaneous works. Juvenilia.
    - [Symphonic ballad, orchestra, op. 24], 1 score (51, [1] p.); 35 cm. (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Symphonic piece for chamber orchestra, op. 49.
      See: Symphony in miniature, op. 49.
    - [Symphony, no. 1, op. 28, F minor] Symphony for full orchestra in F minor. 1910 Nov 7
      - [Symphony, no. 1, op. 28, F minor] Symphony for full orchestra in F minor. 1910 Nov 7, 1 score (215 p.), bound; 42 cm. (Box 30)
        "Dedicated to my friend and teacher Horatio Parker..." -- title page.
      - [Symphony, no. 1, op. 28, F minor] Symphony for full orchestra in F minor. 1910 Nov 7, 1 score (216 p. [extra pp. 213-214 and 1 sheet at end]; 35 cm. (Box 9, Folder 52)
        Holograph signed, in pencil with corrections.
        On p. 214 (second series): Toledo, August 13, 1910.
      - [Symphony, no. 1, op. 28, F minor] Symphony for full orchestra in F minor. 1910 Nov 7, 53 parts; 35 cm. (Box 9, Folder 53-58)
    - [Symphony, no. 2, op. 42, D major] 1917-1919
      - [Symphony, no. 2, op. 42, D major] 1917-1919, 1 score (130 p.), bound; 42 cm. (Box 31)
        "Affectionately dedicated to my Father" -- title page.
      - [Symphony, no. 2, op. 42, D major] 1917-1919, 61 parts; 35 cm. (Box 10, Folder 59-63)
        String parts printed, but with revised ending manuscript, other parts manuscript in ink.
      - [Symphony, no. 2, op. 42, D major] 1917-1919, 28 string parts; 34 cm. (Box 10, Folder 64-65)
        Photocopies from manuscript, in part with markings. One 'cello part has corrections in David Stanley Smith's hand.
    - [Symphony, no. 3, op. 60, C minor] 1928 Oct 5
      - [Symphony, no. 3, op. 60, C minor] 1928 Oct 5, 1 score (144 p.), bound; 42 cm. (Box 31)
        Program of performance by the Cleveland orchestra (1931 Jun 8, 10) laid in.
      - [Symphony, no. 3, op. 60, C minor] 1928 Oct 5, 59 parts; 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 66-68)
    - [Symphony, no. 4, op. 78, D minor] 1937-1940
      See also: E. Keyboard works. Symphony, no. 4, op. 78, D minor; arr.
      - [Symphony, no. 4, op. 78, D minor] 1937-1940, 1 score (172 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 68)
      - [Symphony, no. 4, op. 78, D minor] 1937-1940, 1 score (172 sheets); 30 cm. (Box 11, Folder 69)
        Photocopy (negative) of above holograph score.
        Pages 16-18 omitted, having been cancelled in the holograph.
      - [Symphony, no. 4, op. 78, D minor] 1937-1940, 64 parts; 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 70-71)
        Manuscript in ink. part signed holographs and photocopies.
      - [Symphony, no. 4, op. 78, D minor] 1937-1940, 17 parts; 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 72-75)
        Mainly photocopies of manuscript, a few holographs in ink.
    - [Symphony, no. 5, op. 99, E flat] 1948 Feb 26
      - [Symphony, no. 5, op. 99, E flat] 1948 Feb 26, 1 score (180 p.); 39 cm. (Box 12, Folder 76)
        At head of title: To Bruce Simonds.
      - [Symphony, no. 5, op. 99, E flat] 1948 Feb 26, 2 scores (180 p.), bound; 39 cm. (Box 31)
        Photocopy of above holograph score, with changes.
      - [Symphony, no. 5, op. 99, E flat] 1948 Feb 26, 5 string parts; 32 cm. (Box 12, Folder 77)
      - [Symphony, no. 5, op. 99, E flat] 1948 Feb 26, 63 parts; 32 cm. (Box 12; 13, Folder 78-79; 80-81)
        Photocopies and holographs signed, in ink.
    - [Symphony, no. 5, op. 99, E flat (Revisions)] 1948 Oct, [3] sheets, [1] sheet, [1] sheet of music; 21-28 cm. (Box 12, Folder 82)
      Holographs signed, in ink and pencil.
    - [Symphony, no. 5, op. 99, E flat (Sketches)], [3] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 83)
      See also: E. Keyboard works. Symphony, no. 5, op. 99, E flat; arr.
    - [Symphony, op. 9, C minor] 1902 Nov, 1 score (168 p.), bound; 34 cm. (Box 13)
      The first symphony composed by David Stanley Smith; its two middle movements became L'allegro and il penseroso.
      With: sketches for lst, 2nd, and 4th movements, dated 1902.
      See also: L'allegro and il penseroso, orchestra, op. 9.
    - [Symphony in miniature, op. 49]
      - [Symphony in miniature, op. 49], 1 score (79 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 13, Folder 83)
      - [Symphony in miniature, op. 49], 18 parts; 35 cm. (Box 13, Folder 84)
    - [Tomorrow, orchestra, op. 66, no. 2] 1933 Aug
      - Yesterday and Tomorrow: two compositions for orchestra., 1 score (59 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 13)
        Contents: No. 1, 1929 - A satire; No. 2, Tomorrow - an overture.
      - "Tomorrow": an overture., 54 parts; 35 cm. (Box 13, Folder 85-86)
    - [Tomorrow, orchestra, op. 66, no. 2 (Sketches)], [1], 12, [2] p. of music, bound; 32 cm. (Box 14, Folder 96)
      Included in sketchbook with: Concerto, violin, op. 69, no. 1.
    - [Vienna invicta, orchestra, op. 85] Vienna invicta: waltz-rondo for orchestra. 1941 Aug 7
      - [Vienna invicta, orchestra, op. 85] Vienna invicta: waltz-rondo for orchestra. 1941 Aug 7, 1 score (58 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 13)
      - [Vienna invicta, orchestra, op. 85] Vienna invicta: waltz-rondo for orchestra. 1941 Aug 7, 20 string parts; 32 cm. (Box 14, Folder 87)
      - [Vienna invicta, orchestra, op. 85] Vienna invicta: waltz-rondo for orchestra. 1941 Aug 7, 85 parts; 35 cm. (Box 14, Folder 88-89)
        Holographs signed, in ink and photocopies of holograph.
    - Waltz-rondo, orchestra, op. 85.
      See: Vienna invicta, orchestra, op. 85.
    - Yesterday and Tomorrow, orchestra.
      See: Nineteen-twenty-nine, orchestra, op. 66, no. 1; and Tomorrow, op. 66, no. 2.
    - Unidentified loose sheets, orchestra., [2] p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 90)
      Holographs in ink.
  - Solo instrument / voice with orchestra, I.B
    - [Cathedral prelude, organ, orchestra, op. 54] 1925 Jan-Oct
      - [Cathedral prelude, organ, orchestra, op. 54] 1925 Jan-Oct, 1 score (56.p.), bound; 42 cm. (Box 31)
      - [Cathedral prelude, organ, orchestra, op. 54] 1925 Jan-Oct, 49 parts; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 91-92)
    - [Concerto, violin, orchestra, op. 69, F] 1933 Jul 14
      - [Concerto, violin, orchestra, op. 69, F] 1933 Jul 14, 1 score (66 p.), bound; 35 cm.
      - [Concerto, violin, orchestra, op. 69, F] 1933 Jul 14, 1 score (70 p.); 35 cm. (Box 14, Folder 93)
      - [Concerto, violin, orchestra, op. 69, F] 1933 Jul 14, 49 parts; 35 cm. (Box 14, Folder 94-95)
    - [Concerto, violin, orchestra, op. 69, F (Sketches)], 15, 12, [2] p. of music, bound; 32 cm. (Box 14, Folder 96)
    - [Concerto, violin, orchestra, op. 86, G] 1942 Feb 28, 1 score (101 p.); 35 cm. (Box 14, Folder 97)
    - [Concerto, violin, orchestra, op. 86, G (Sketches)], 1 condensed score (23 p.); 35 cm. (Box 14, Folder 98)
    - [Fête galante, flute, orchestra, op. 48] Fête galante (after Watteau): for flute and orchestra. 1921 Feb 2
      - [Fête galante, flute, orchestra, op. 48] Fête galante (after Watteau): for flute and orchestra. 1921 Feb 2, 1 score (35 p.), bound; 41 cm. (Box 31)
        Original version.
      - [Fête galante, flute, orchestra, op. 48] Fête galante (after Watteau): for flute and orchestra. 1921 Feb 2, 18 parts; various sizes (Box 15, Folder 99)
        Original version in D flat major.